A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of Adrienne Germain FA567
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, International Division, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of Adrienne Germain
1976-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Germain, Adrienne
Ford Foundation
FA567
2.7 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Arranged is 2 series by Correspondence type.
Collection arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Chronological Correspondence, 1977-1980
Series II. Alphabetical Correspondence, 1976-1978
Scope and Contents
Chronological and Alphabetical correspondence
Biographical / Historical
Adrienne Germain is a women's health activist and researcher who worked for several years at the Ford Foundation. While at the Foundation, Germain's work focused on programs and projects concerning population and women, and in 1981, she became the Foundation's Representative for Bangladesh. Germain was appointed President of the International Women's Health Coalition (IWHC) in 1998 and served in that position until 2012.
Between 1972 and 1975, Germain worked in the Ford Foundation's Population Program as an Assistant Program Officer and then a Program Officer. After that, she became a Project Specialist in the International Division, Office of the Vice President. In that position, she was responsible for assisting projects focused on women as well as for integrating a concern about women with Foundation supported projects involving agriculture, population, and education in Asia, Africa, Latin America, and the Caribbean (Correspondence from Adrienne Germain to Wynante Patterson, January 6, 1977, Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 3255-6261 (FA739B), Report 005016). Germaine became the Foundation's Representative for Bangladesh in 1981 and was based at the Foundation's Dhaka office.
After leaving the Ford Foundation, Germain joined the International Women's Health Coalition (IWHC) as Vice President in 1985. She became President of the organization in 1998. She retired from that position in 2012.
Germain earned a Bachelor's Degree from Wellesley College and a Master's Degree in sociology and demography from the University of California, Berkeley.
- Chronological Correspondence, 1977-1980; I
  - Chrons, 1977 September (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1977 October (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1977 November (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1977 December (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1978 January (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1978 February (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1978 March (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1978 April (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1978 May (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1979 January (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1979 February (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1979 March (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1979 April (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1979 May (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1979 June (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1979 July (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1979 August (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1979 September (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1979 October (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1979 November (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1979 December (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1980 January (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1980 February (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1980 March (Box 1)
  - Chrons, 1980 April (Box 1)
- Alphabetical Correspondence, 1976-1978; II
  Scope and Contents
  All correspondence is prior to 1979.
  - A, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - B, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - C, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - D, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - E, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - F, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - G, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - H, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - I, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - J, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - K, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - L, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - Mc, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - M, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - N, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - O, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - P, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - Q, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - R, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - S (1/2), 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - S (2/2), 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - T, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - U, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - V, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - W, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - X-Y-Z, 1976-1978 (Box 2)